<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PapaScott<</title>
    <link>http://www.papascott.de/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.papascott.de/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>A personal weblog by Scott Hanson</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 07:28:27 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 07:28:27 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future Is Now</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/07/the-future-is-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 07:03:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/07/the-future-is-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were closed 11 days for construction, but now our restaurant in Dibbersen has been opened for 3 days as a “Restaurant of the Future” and so far we are very happy with it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/rdz-kiosks-061116.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;alignright&quot; /&gt; The first thing you notice as a guest is the brighter, more spacious lobby, as well as the self-service terminals, or kiosks. There you can enter your order and pay by either card or cash. Of course you can still go to the cashier and verbally give your order just as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing you notice is that the cashier does not then go to assemble your order. There is a separate station for that, and you can either go there to pick up your order, or you can choose table service. You pick up a chip, find a table, and thanks to the magic of bluetooth we can find your table and bring your order to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third thing you notice is that all burgers are made fresh to order. This “Made For You” system has been running for years in the US, but is new in Germany. The heated bin&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; where products could be kept for 10 minutes is now history. Our products are now made one at time instead of an entire tray at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were wondering how quickly we could adjust to the new system, but the first 3 days went very well. The kitchen is more organized and less hectic, and even it gets full we can recover quite quickly. In service our people enjoy that they now have time and opportunity to talk to our guests, and with our new look and new system they have plenty to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even I learned enough about the new system that I can help out in the kitchen without messing everything up. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Funny how in US English a bin is where you put things to keep, but in UK English a bin is where you put things to throw away. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Clinton Wins</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/02/if-clinton-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 11:10:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/02/if-clinton-wins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago Dave Winer wrote a piece about &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/10/30/imOkayWithTrumpWinning.html&quot;&gt;Trump winning&lt;/a&gt;. So what if Clinton wins?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be like the status quo only worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large group of Trump who feel estranged from the system will still feel estranged. This estrangement is certainly not exclusively American, see Brexit, the &lt;em&gt;Front National&lt;/em&gt;, or the &lt;em&gt;Alternativ für Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. This group will remain and I doubt that Clinton is the type of leader that can win them back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republican party will remain dysfunctional, maybe even to the point that no Supreme Court justices will be confirmed at all. Look forward to more standstill and government shutdowns. The “Lock Her Up” faction will not become silent, they’ll probably become louder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abroad, relations with Russia will continue to worsen and the conflicts of the world will continue, with new ones arising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, though, we’ll be pretty happy with it, because &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/10/30/imOkayWithTrumpWinning.html&quot;&gt;it could have been much worse!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expecting</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/01/expecting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 10:56:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/01/expecting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this All Saints’ Day we are happy and proud to announce that we are expecting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, no, that’s not right… damn you auto-correct, we’re too old for that. No, we are happy and proud to announce that we are &lt;em&gt;expanding&lt;/em&gt;, in Hamburg-Harburg!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/phxarc-011116.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On December 1st we will be purchasing the existing McDonald’s restaurants in Phoenix Center and Harburg Arcaden. They are so-called satellites, located in shopping centers with a limited menu and low volume (about 1/3 the sales of a free-standing restaurant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already own the Marktkauf Center satellite in Harburg, and all three stores are just a couple hundred meters apart. Our store manager there will now have her hands full with triplets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as we are right now converting our restaurant in Dibbersen to Restaurant of the Future (re-opening on Friday!) with Winsener Straße to follow in February, Frauke and I have our hands full too! :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Done!</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/10/31/done/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 18:14:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/10/31/done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It took 10 years to build and is 10 times over budget, but the Hamburg’s new concert hall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elbphilharmonie.de/en/elbphilharmonie&quot;&gt;Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; in the HafenCity is complete. The first concert is in January, but the builders handed it over to the city today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Live from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Hamburg?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Hamburg&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Elbphilharmonie?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; is ready for opening (window lighting reads &amp;#39;DONE&amp;#39; in German: FERTIG) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/l5pLLaBSkS&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/l5pLLaBSkS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Thomas Michael G. (@ThomasMichaelGe) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ThomasMichaelGe/status/793127825909878785&quot;&gt;October 31, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the day it looks more like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;de&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hoffentlich schwindelfrei ;) Fensterputzer an der &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Elbphilharmonie?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/RX3IYSu8XU&quot;&gt;https://t.co/RX3IYSu8XU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bild: Marek Santen &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/v5Mc6sLJal&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/v5Mc6sLJal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; hamburg.de (@hamburg_de) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hamburg_de/status/793082218545635328&quot;&gt;October 31, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stupid Majority</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/23/the-stupid-majority/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 21:23:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/23/the-stupid-majority/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This election is a good reminder of the basic principles of democracy: stupid people vote. Not only that, any democracy is ruled by a stupid majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it. If you believe that you are of above-average intelligence, and who of us doesn’t, then by definition there is a majority of voters more stupid than you. And since stupid people generally don’t recognize their own stupidity, almost every one of us is faced with a stupid majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are stupid, and you know it, you can rest assured that there is a smart majority out there to make the decisions for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the average person, of average intelligence, the average person has a great responsibility. They have the deciding vote. They decide whether the majority is smart or stupid. Our fate rests in their hands. May they choose wisely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they can’t. They are only of average intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we are doomed to be ruled by a stupid majority. But that is not altogether a bad thing. All the political systems where only smart people make decisions have failed very badly. It is the stupid people who save us from ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And I bet you thought a post with this title would be about Trump supporters. Or Clinton supporters. Fooled you!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fifteen Years On</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/11/fifteen-years-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 21:02:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/11/fifteen-years-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/nyTimesHomeBombing7AM2.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/nyt-110916.gif&quot; alt=&quot;New York Times Screenshot 9-11-2001 via scripting.com &quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This screenshot from &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/nyTimesHomeBombing7AM2.gif&quot;&gt;scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; is pretty much how I first learned the the 9/11 attacks. A low-res picture on a news website from my office in Hamburg. 3 in the afternoon. The next day I was able to put my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/12/the-day-the-earth-stood-still/&quot;&gt;thoughts into words&lt;/a&gt;. More or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And next day came the headline in the Hamburg newspaper &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/13/were-in-this-together/&quot;&gt;“Americans! We are with you!”&lt;/a&gt;, and at the same time, the first clue that the attackers came from Hamburg. All I knew then was that my country and world would never be the same again. I was far away, and grateful for the internet where I could at least try to fathom how the country I had left a few years before was changing. Without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And today. My son who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/16/sunday-at-home/&quot;&gt;was an 1 year old then&lt;/a&gt; is now 16, nearly an adult. My country started two wars in revenge that solved nothing, made everything worse, and haven’t really yet ended. Mission not accomplished. The current round of politics and presidential candidates don’t seem to offer much hope of any improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think I’ll just listen to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brucespringsteen.net/albums/the-rising&quot;&gt;The Rising&lt;/a&gt; a couple times through to remind of me of how I felt and how things could have become better. But didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vinyl Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/06/vinyl-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 09:47:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/06/vinyl-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is our 33rd anniversary. In 4 months it will be 33-1/3. Then it will be a LP record.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Million Euro Overdraft</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/08/05/million-euro-overdraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 18:56:33 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/08/05/million-euro-overdraft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This happened over 9 years ago, I think it’s safe to tell the story now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my wife bought our first restaurant, she set up a corporation (GmbH) for the new business. However, our lawyer was lazy, or slow, or something, and for our start of business the registration of the GmbH had not yet been approved by the local court. No registration, no firm, no business loan could be paid out. With a 7-figure purchase price due that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No problem, says the bank, we’ll book the purchase from your private account, even though our account balance was more like 3 figures and not 7. We’ll increase your overdraft limit until the GmbH gets registered. No problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to this day I have a screenshot of electronic banking with an balance that day of minus one million Euros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought that was pretty funny until we tried to buy groceries and our bank card got denied. We had to call the bank again to increase our limit a bit more so we could eat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1999.io is simple.  And simple.</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/05/05/1999io-is-simple-and-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 10:43:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/05/05/1999io-is-simple-and-simple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks I’ve been trying out &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/05/04/1238.html&quot;&gt;1999.io&lt;/a&gt;, the new blogging software by Dave Winer. You can either try it out at his site &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.1999.io&quot;&gt;my.1999.io&lt;/a&gt; (you just need a Twitter ID to log in) or you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/1999-project/blob/master/docs/setup.md&quot;&gt;install the server&lt;/a&gt; on any system that can run Node. Being a server guy I of course installed my own (on a cheap 3.50€‚/mo VPS), and used it to write my last few blog posts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like it because because it’s simple. And simple. Simple to write with, simple to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple to write with. You just open the editor page and type. To update your text, you just click on it and type. There are some simple formatting options, but nothing that gets in the way. When you update, though WebSocket magic anyone reading your post immediately gets the update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on the server it’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.1999.io/users/1999io/2016/04/11/0004.html&quot;&gt;simple to work with&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no database, just files in open formats readable as text, JSON, OPML, RSS, HTML. Formats you can use for other purposes if you are so inclined. Even the HTML files for each post contain the JSON for the post, which I first thought was redundant but now see is brilliant. It’s like the web page contains it’s own DNA and can re-create itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These open formats allow one to do things with the output that go beyond the server. For instance, I copy the output of my server to an S3 bucket at &lt;a href=&quot;http://1999.papascott.de&quot;&gt;1999.papascott.de&lt;/a&gt;, which can probably handle load better than my cheap VPS :smile:. It’s not yet coupled to my main blog on Jekyll (right now I’m using copy and paste), but I imagine it wouldn’t too much cleverness to achieve that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope someday to be able to use 1999.io as a blogging central, with the ability to send my posts to my blog, or Twitter, or Facebook, or Medium, or wherever, but keeping my original posts for myself. I’ll let those big silos show my work, but not own it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gliding 2</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/27/gliding-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 18:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/27/gliding-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nsF-UrqqkSQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how our son stays out of trouble on weekends. At 16 in Germany he can fly solo, but yet not drive a car. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build 3000 pages in Jekyll in less than 4 seconds</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/25/how-to-build-3000-pages-in-jekyll-in-less-than-4-seconds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 09:24:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/25/how-to-build-3000-pages-in-jekyll-in-less-than-4-seconds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I converted my Wordpress blog to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. My 16 years of blogging are now saved as text files which Jekyll renders into static HTML, which I then push to GitHub where the blog is now hosted. I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/30/see-what-sticks/&quot;&gt;mentioned then&lt;/a&gt; that it took Jekyll some 3 minutes to render my 3000 or so blog posts, which is kind of a drag since the default is to rebuild the entire site every time even a small change is made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, the latest version of Jekyll improved build times considerably. It can now build my 3000 pages in about a minute. But when making changes, that’s still too long to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, using a trick, I can now build those 3000 pages in 4 seconds. The trick seems pretty obvious to me, but I’ve not seen it written up anyplace, so hence this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick, of course, is to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; build all 3000 pages. For older posts use &lt;a href=&quot;https://jquery.com/&quot;&gt;jquery&lt;/a&gt; to load in parts of the layout that might change, but leave the HTML file alone. For me, those parts are the sidebar and the recent posts. I build HTML snippets for those divs and load them in like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$( &quot;#sidebar&quot; ).load( &quot;/includes/sidebar.html&quot; );
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, on the Jekyll side I don’t want it to rebuild posts from before 2015. I’ve put all those in a _posts/older subdirectory and added an exclude: directive in my _config.yml:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;exclude: [_posts/older]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the HTML side, ever since I started blogging, even way-back-when with &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1999/12/08/editthispagecom.html&quot;&gt;EditThisPage&lt;/a&gt;, my posts have been sorted by date. I need to tell Jekyll not to erase the pages I’ve chosen not to rebuild (and it’s too bad _config.yml doesn’t understand wild cards)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;keep_files: [archives/1999, archives/200, archives/2010, archives/2011, archives/2012, archives/2013, archives/2014 ]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least “archives/200” covers an entire decade in one entry. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it. When I do want to rebuild to entire site, I can comment out those two directives and let ‘er rip. And being hosted at GitHub, you can see all my gory source files in the source branch at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/papascott/papascott.github.io&quot;&gt;https://github.com/papascott/papascott.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prince</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/23/prince/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 23:03:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/23/prince/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was dreamin’ when I wrote this, forgive me if it goes astray…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I lived in Minneapolis, I used to think we were cooler than everyone else because we had our own resident musical genius. That’s not true of course, but he &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startribune.com/prince-was-one-of-our-own-and-he-made-minnesota-seem-cool/376798251/&quot;&gt;made us seem cool&lt;/a&gt;. And even after he was rich and famous, he stayed in Minnesota. Most of the time, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now in Europe, even before last week I could say I’m from Minnesota “where Prince is from”, and for a few moments I’m hip and cool. At least until we change the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And maybe, even though I was just a casual fan, that’s why his death has saddened me. I’ve lost a piece of home. &lt;em&gt;Ich habe ein Stück Heimat verloren.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, I keep a copy of Dirty Mind (1980) on my current mobile device. It was my first Prince record. It’s an imperfect album. It’s sparsely produced, it almost sounds like a demo. And the lyrics, well, Prince was the artist for whom the term “explicit content” was invented, and they distract from the music. But it’s tight. Every note, every beat, on every track hits. Just listen to the 2nd side (this was back when albums had sides), with Uptown-Head-Sister-Partyup, beginning to end. It still blows me away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(My favorite track, though, is on the first side, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/When_You_Were_Mine_(Prince_song)&quot;&gt;When You Were Mine&lt;/a&gt;. Mr. LoveSexy turns into a bat-shit-crazy ex. Both funny and sexy as hell.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ants</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/18/the-ants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 17:40:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/18/the-ants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our house turns 20 years old this year. And every spring the same thing happens. The ants come into the kitchen for a few weeks. Then they disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ours is a good, solid German house, made of brick. But we live out in the country, and out in the country one has to deal with critters and creepy-crawly things. The doors and windows are tight, but there is obviously a crack in the outside wall to the kitchen. Every spring the ants wake up, get hungry, come inside the wall, and then maybe behind the cabinets, and find an entry to the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year they find a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; entry. I’ve heard that ants have collective intelligence, and that it’s probably passed down from generation to generation. They are probably more intelligent than we, since every year we forget that the ants are coming. And then it takes us several days to find their point of entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we can’t think like ants, we have to wait until a whole bunch of them have come in so we can see their trail. Then we get out the ant spray, secure the entry, and wait a few days see if they find a new entry and come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They usually don’t. The spring weather gets warmer, and I presume the ants then find it easier to find their food outside rather than risk encountering ant spray inside. But they have the knowledge of how to get into our kitchen, and their offspring will use that knowledge next year, to find a new entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is this year’s point of entry, and our weapon of choice. We’re planning on renovating our kitchen this year. Maybe we’ll find that crack in the wall and get it patched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ants-180416.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Ants&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Exchange</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/05/student-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 19:50:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/05/student-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have an exchange student from Italy with us this week (his family hosted our son for a week last fall). We were a bit worried about how to keep him occupied, since we’re out in the country and far from the school. We needn’t have worried. The students (hosts and guests) hang out in Lüneburg after school and they only come home to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, German is cool in that it was a different word for grade and high school students &lt;em&gt;(Schüler)&lt;/em&gt; than for college students &lt;em&gt;(Studenten)&lt;/em&gt;. We’re talking about &lt;em&gt;Schüler&lt;/em&gt; here. And that my wife and I met when she was an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2009/11/17/and-i-saw-her-standing-there/&quot;&gt;exchange student&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Schüler)&lt;/em&gt; in Minnesota is totally beside the point!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gliding</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/05/gliding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 08:43:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/05/gliding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;6&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BDvxkgOo_e-/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Great shot by my flight instructor @simon_bacher 42 minutes in blue thermals and lots of spinning 😰😅 #segelfliegen #gliding #soaring #thermik #blauthermik #thermals #900m #wenzendorf #ask13 #d8964 #segelflugzeug #glider #sailplane #gopro #gopropilots_ #sobock #soobock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Christopher Hanson (@fseddh) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-04-03T17:27:53+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 3, 2016 at 10:27am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where and For Whom to Vote</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/02/19/where-and-for-whom-to-vote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 17:48:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/02/19/where-and-for-whom-to-vote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Will_Rogers&quot;&gt;Will Rogers&lt;/a&gt;, I am proud to not be a member of any organized political party. I am a Democrat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And true to that spirit, as a Democrat living outside the United States, for the current presidential campaign I not only have to decide for whom to vote, but also where. (For my foreign readers following the US election, yes the process is complicated, and my description will make the impression that it is even more complicated. That is deliberate on my part.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can vote (in my last state of residence) in the Arizona presidential primary on March 22 (which, by the way, is not a primary but instead a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.azsos.gov/elections/voting-election/election-information&quot;&gt;presidential preference election&lt;/a&gt;, since the actual primary for state and local candidates is in August). However, the Democrats have an organization for Democrats living abroad (called, appropriately enough, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.democratsabroad.org/&quot;&gt;Democrats Abroad&lt;/a&gt;) which is entitled to send delegates to the Democratic National Convention. Eight of those delegates are superdelegates, beholden to no one but themselves, but thirteen delegates are pledged. And to choose those pledged delegates, they hold the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.democratsabroad.org/the_global_presidential_primary_is_now_vote&quot;&gt;Democrats Abroad Global Presidential Primary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just like in an official presidential primary (or preference election), I can even go to a real polling place to vote. In Hamburg! On March 5! At the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.democratsabroad.org/848/hamburg_global_presidential_primary&quot;&gt;Friedrich Ebert Stiftung on Rathausmarkt!&lt;/a&gt; (hold on, are we in cahoots with the German SPD on this?) Or at a number of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.democratsabroad.org/bseebach/democrats_abroad_germany_global_primary_locations&quot;&gt;other locations in Germany&lt;/a&gt;, or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://d3n8a8pro7vhmx.cloudfront.net/democratsabroad/pages/4823/attachments/original/1454667653/VotingCenters2016.pdf&quot;&gt;around the world&lt;/a&gt;. If wasn’t already a member of Democrats Abroad, I could join on-site at the polling place. If I couldn’t make it to a polling place, I could vote remotely, by email, fax or snail mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while I could vote in my former home state of Arizona, it makes more sense for me to vote in the global primary, since we Americans abroad have unique issues for our candidates to be aware of (like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howtogermany.com/pages/ustaxes.html&quot;&gt;taxation&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreign_Account_Tax_Compliance_Act&quot;&gt;FATCA&lt;/a&gt;, and taxation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I know where I will vote. Now I just have to decide for whom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In all fairness, there is also an organization for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/republicansoverseas/&quot;&gt;Republicans abroad&lt;/a&gt;, but you guys don’t get a primary. You’re not even officially part of the Republican party. Sorry.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will You Still Love Me When I'm Fifty-Four?</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/02/13/will-you-still-love-me-when-im-fiftyfour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 09:45:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/02/13/will-you-still-love-me-when-im-fiftyfour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fifty-four-130216.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aged 54 years&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the answer is yes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anniversary</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/09/06/anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/09/06/anniversary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to write a blog post for our anniversary each year. Nowadays I just use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10153422228986281&amp;amp;set=a.10150156329816281.333920.666521280&amp;amp;type=1&amp;amp;theater&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;32 years together and still going strong! &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/aWQZ5emsuy&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/aWQZ5emsuy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Scott Hanson (@papascott) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/papascott/status/640436611323424768&quot;&gt;September 6, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25 Years</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/09/01/25-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/09/01/25-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another half decade, another milestone. Just five years ago I was waxing poetic about &lt;a href=&quot;/archives/2010/09/01/it-was-twenty-years-ago-today/&quot;&gt;how we had already been in Germany for 20 years&lt;/a&gt;, and now it’s already been 25 years. Strangely enough my passport from then bears no entry stamp for 1 September 1990.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time our entry into Germany was uncertain. Reunification was in the air, everyone knew it was coming, but the details were still being negotiated behind closed doors. We boarded our plane to Frankfurt on 31 August without knowing our fate. Luckily for us, while our plane was in the air, the “Einigungsvertrag” was signed by BRD Interior Minister Wolfgang Schäuble and DDR State Secretary Günter Krause, clearing the way for our entry into the soon-to-be unified Germany the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bundesfinanzministerium.de/Content/DE/Bilder/Bildstrecken/Mediathek/Bildergalerien/Bewegte_Zeiten/Galerie01_11.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.bundesfinanzministerium.de/Content/DE/Bilder/Bildstrecken/Mediathek/Bildergalerien/Bewegte_Zeiten/Galerie01_11.jpg?__blob=normal&amp;amp;v=4&quot; alt=&quot;Einigungsvertrag 31-Aug-1990&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That document did however leave several details open. It never was determined whether our cats would remain American citizens or whether they would obtain German citizenship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking your Place</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/05/25/taking-your-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/05/25/taking-your-place/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For our son’s Confirmation yesterday I gave a toast that went quite well. It sums up pretty well how I feel right now about our son and parenting, so I’ve modified it a bit and posted it. I wrote it in English so my mother could follow along, but I gave it in German, translating on my feet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to take this chance to talk directly to you, my son. This is one of the few chances that I know you’ll be listening. At church the pastor talked about how Confirmation is a decision, an active decision, that you make. It is also an positive action… you are finding and &lt;em&gt;taking your place&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are of course &lt;em&gt;taking your place in the church&lt;/em&gt;. We were all just there, of course. The church is a human institution, of course, it is not perfect. But the humans in the church usually do the best they can. And the church has been around a couple of thousand years… if you have a question or a problem, chances are someone has come to the church with that before and it can give you advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confirmation is also a family event. They have all come to celebrate not so much because they are interested in your faith but because you are &lt;em&gt;taking your place in your family&lt;/em&gt;. Confirmation has played a role in both our families, in Germany and in the US, and is something that binds them both. It is a family milestone, a sign of a new generation, and time and life moves on as it always has. Time only moves in one direction and at one speed. It always gets to its destination, even when we want to take detours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In rural Germany Confirmation is also a community event, much more so than in the US. It is the line you cross to become an adult. For your parents our town is a place we moved to, but for you it is where you grew up, your home, your &lt;em&gt;Heimat&lt;/em&gt;. And now you will be &lt;em&gt;taking your place in your community&lt;/em&gt;. You will no longer sing for candy on Pentecost, but plant trees with the young men. Later you can graduate from the youth fire dept to take responsibility for your community with the active fire dept. A hometown is something precious. A place where you can put down roots, find your peace, a place to belong. Your older relatives can tell what it is like to lose your hometown, your &lt;em&gt;Heimat&lt;/em&gt;. It is something to be cherished in your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you are &lt;em&gt;taking your place in world&lt;/em&gt;. Unlike in our town, in reality becoming an adult is not a solid line to be crossed. It’s a process that you have now started, and maybe never ends, and process that you are now taking over for yourself. For your parents it means that we have taught you pretty much even thing we can, we cannot “raise” you anymore. We can’t tell you anything anymore, as you remind us when we try to say something you disagree with. We have to start letting go, to stop setting rules and instead give advice and let you make your own mistakes. We are very happy and very proud for what you are and what you will become. I am certain that you have the qualities for success, in every sense of the word. Your self-confidence, your sense of fairness, your intelligence and stubbornness… a positive stubbornness, I should point out. It’s OK to dream big, that’s the only way big dreams can come true, just have a flight plan filed, just in case. As pilots say, flying is the second most exciting thing in life. The most exciting thing is landing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is your day. Cheers, &lt;em&gt;Prost&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;auf Dich&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See What Sticks</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/30/see-what-sticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/30/see-what-sticks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So now that I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;/archives/2015/04/23/transition/&quot;&gt;changed&lt;/a&gt; my blogging platform, I have something to blog about: my new blogging platform!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the WordPress eXtended RSS file of the contents of my blog I found I had exported 3273 posts. Jekyll re-renders every post every time a change is made… on the default template it takes 3 minutes, but on the Lanyon template it ran over 20 minutes before I cancelled the build. That’s why I started with only a few dozen posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then changed my archive strategy, using yearly and monthly archives similar to what I had used with WordPress instead of the pagination used in Lanyon, and lo and behold the build took only 2.5 minutes. The disadvantage is that GitHub won’t run the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-archives&quot;&gt;jekyll-archives&lt;/a&gt; plugin for me, so I have to render the site locally and push the rendered HTML to GitHub. I can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next question was whether Google (and everyone else) could find the old links on the new site. Jekyll is able to use the same &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;archives/:year/:month/:day/:title/&lt;/code&gt; permalink stucture I was using before. But were all my links the same as before? Do they all still work? Well, that eXtended RSS file contains all the permalinks that WordPress had generated…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;http://papasc.home/archives/1999/12/05/it-worked/&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;http://papasc.home/archives/1999/12/06/week-37/&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;http://papasc.home/archives/1999/12/07/ready-and-waiting/&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;http://papasc.home/archives/1999/12/09/linux-fever/&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;
 ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Yes, that’s a fake URL. My hoster timed out producing the eXtended RSS file so I had to use a local install.) I then ran the links through a shell script I found on &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/25135347/how-to-check-status-of-urls-from-text-file-using-bash-shell-script&quot;&gt;Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;read&lt;/span&gt; -ru 4 LINE; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do
     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;read&lt;/span&gt; -r REP &amp;lt; &amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exec &lt;/span&gt;curl -IsS &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$LINE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt; 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
     &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$LINE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$REP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;done &lt;/span&gt;4&amp;lt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, indeed, all the links work. Whether the content still makes sense is another question, but PapaScott is back online in its entirety!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transition</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/23/transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/23/transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So maybe you noticed, maybe you didn’t, but this blog looks a little bit different than a week ago. Behind the scenes it looks a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; different. After over a decade of blogging on WordPress (I actually started using its predecessor &lt;a href=&quot;http://cafelog.com/&quot;&gt;B2&lt;/a&gt; in 2002), I’m now on the static site generator jekyll. My posts have been exported to text files. No more mysql database, no PHP, no more web interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So everything is new and things are still broken. I don’t have all posts imported yet, I’m only back to 2012 and not 1999 when this thing started. There are a lot a worthless one-line posts from the olden days, since back then we didn’t have Twitter and Facebook yet for worthless posts. So I have some work to do. But I’m looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design, however, is absolutely fabulous, even on mobile, and for that I can take absolutely no credit. It’s the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lanyon.getpoole.com/&quot;&gt;lanyon&lt;/a&gt; theme for jekyll by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt;, who co-wrote (Twitter) &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, and I thank him for making his work available to us mere mortals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirmation</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/20/confirmation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/20/confirmation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://policke1.p2-men.de/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/policke-200415.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Policke&quot; class=&quot;alignright&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Last week we bought a confirmation suit. Of course we went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://policke1.p2-men.de/&quot;&gt;Policke&lt;/a&gt; in Hamburg. It’s the perfect place for young (or older) men to shop. It has the feel of a 1920s haberdasher, full of dark little rooms connected by narrow halls and staircases. You’re met at the front door by the head sizer, who determines your size with a glance and with a slight movement of his eyes directs you to the room where your size is stocked. Once there, you nod at the salesman (they’re all men), who from your nod determines the style and price range you want. You’re in and out in 10 minutes. No words are necessary at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe not quite. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confirmation will be at the end of May, on Pentecost Sunday. My mother will be flying in from the US. My father won’t be there, of course.  He made a huge impression on his grandson, though, despite living an ocean and thousands of miles away. He thought of his grandfather when he chose his confirmation verse*. We also legally added his grandfather’s name as an additional middle name for him. He will carry his grandfather’s name the rest of his life, and he will be confirmed with it next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess my father will be there after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Matthew 7:7 “Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Punked Facebook</title>
      <link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/02/10/how-i-punked-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 07:13:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/02/10/how-i-punked-facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It took me nearly two years, but I finally did it. I was able to get the better of Facebook. Yesterday I was able to celebrate my birthday without a single greeting on social media, even if my wife very nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/papascott/posts/10152947844446281y&quot;&gt;gave me away&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was heaven! It was bliss! I was living free of the distractions of the digital world, if only for one day. My day! For me, me alone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope your day was a good one too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
