<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>PapaScott</title>
		<description>I don&#39;t claim to succeed at all this</description>		
		<link>http://www.papascott.de</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.papascott.de/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>If Clinton Wins</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago Dave Winer wrote a piece about &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/10/30/imOkayWithTrumpWinning.html&quot;&gt;Trump winning&lt;/a&gt;. So what if Clinton wins?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be like the status quo only worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large group of Trump who feel estranged from the system will still feel estranged. This estrangement is certainly not exclusively American, see Brexit, the &lt;em&gt;Front National&lt;/em&gt;, or the &lt;em&gt;Alternativ für Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. This group will remain and I doubt that Clinton is the type of leader that can win them back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republican party will remain dysfunctional, maybe even to the point that no Supreme Court justices will be confirmed at all. Look forward to more standstill and government shutdowns. The “Lock Her Up” faction will not become silent, they’ll probably become louder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abroad, relations with Russia will continue to worsen and the conflicts of the world will continue, with new ones arising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, though, we’ll be pretty happy with it, because &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/10/30/imOkayWithTrumpWinning.html&quot;&gt;it could have been much worse!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 11:10:52 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/02/if-clinton-wins/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/02/if-clinton-wins/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Expecting</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;On this All Saints’ Day we are happy and proud to announce that we are expecting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, no, that’s not right… damn you auto-correct, we’re too old for that. No, we are happy and proud to announce that we are &lt;em&gt;expanding&lt;/em&gt;, in Hamburg-Harburg!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/phxarc-011116.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On December 1st we will be purchasing the existing McDonald’s restaurants in Phoenix Center and Harburg Arcaden. They are so-called satellites, located in shopping centers with a limited menu and low volume (about 1/3 the sales of a free-standing restaurant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already own the Marktkauf Center satellite in Harburg, and all three stores are just a couple hundred meters apart. Our store manager there will now have her hands full with triplets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as we are right now converting our restaurant in Dibbersen to Restaurant of the Future (re-opening on Friday!) with Winsener Straße to follow in February, Frauke and I have our hands full too! :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 10:56:32 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/01/expecting/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/01/expecting/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Done!</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;It took 10 years to build and is 10 times over budget, but the Hamburg’s new concert hall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elbphilharmonie.de/en/elbphilharmonie&quot;&gt;Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; in the HafenCity is complete. The first concert is in January, but the builders handed it over to the city today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Live from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Hamburg?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Hamburg&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Elbphilharmonie?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; is ready for opening (window lighting reads &amp;#39;DONE&amp;#39; in German: FERTIG) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/l5pLLaBSkS&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/l5pLLaBSkS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Thomas Michael G. (@ThomasMichaelGe) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ThomasMichaelGe/status/793127825909878785&quot;&gt;October 31, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the day it looks more like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;de&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hoffentlich schwindelfrei ;) Fensterputzer an der &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Elbphilharmonie?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/RX3IYSu8XU&quot;&gt;https://t.co/RX3IYSu8XU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bild: Marek Santen &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/v5Mc6sLJal&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/v5Mc6sLJal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; hamburg.de (@hamburg_de) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hamburg_de/status/793082218545635328&quot;&gt;October 31, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 18:14:14 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/10/31/done/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/10/31/done/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Stupid Majority</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;This election is a good reminder of the basic principles of democracy: stupid people vote. Not only that, any democracy is ruled by a stupid majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it. If you believe that you are of above-average intelligence, and who of us doesn’t, then by definition there is a majority of voters more stupid than you. And since stupid people generally don’t recognize their own stupidity, almost every one of us is faced with a stupid majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are stupid, and you know it, you can rest assured that there is a smart majority out there to make the decisions for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the average person, of average intelligence, the average person has a great responsibility. They have the deciding vote. They decide whether the majority is smart or stupid. Our fate rests in their hands. May they choose wisely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they can’t. They are only of average intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we are doomed to be ruled by a stupid majority. But that is not altogether a bad thing. All the political systems where only smart people make decisions have failed very badly. It is the stupid people who save us from ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And I bet you thought a post with this title would be about Trump supporters. Or Clinton supporters. Fooled you!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 21:23:55 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/23/the-stupid-majority/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/23/the-stupid-majority/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Fifteen Years On</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/nyTimesHomeBombing7AM2.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/nyt-110916.gif&quot; alt=&quot;New York Times Screenshot 9-11-2001 via scripting.com &quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This screenshot from &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/nyTimesHomeBombing7AM2.gif&quot;&gt;scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; is pretty much how I first learned the the 9/11 attacks. A low-res picture on a news website from my office in Hamburg. 3 in the afternoon. The next day I was able to put my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/12/the-day-the-earth-stood-still/&quot;&gt;thoughts into words&lt;/a&gt;. More or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And next day came the headline in the Hamburg newspaper &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/13/were-in-this-together/&quot;&gt;“Americans! We are with you!”&lt;/a&gt;, and at the same time, the first clue that the attackers came from Hamburg. All I knew then was that my country and world would never be the same again. I was far away, and grateful for the internet where I could at least try to fathom how the country I had left a few years before was changing. Without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And today. My son who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/16/sunday-at-home/&quot;&gt;was an 1 year old then&lt;/a&gt; is now 16, nearly an adult. My country started two wars in revenge that solved nothing, made everything worse, and haven’t really yet ended. Mission not accomplished. The current round of politics and presidential candidates don’t seem to offer much hope of any improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think I’ll just listen to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brucespringsteen.net/albums/the-rising&quot;&gt;The Rising&lt;/a&gt; a couple times through to remind of me of how I felt and how things could have become better. But didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 21:02:52 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/11/fifteen-years-on/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/11/fifteen-years-on/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Vinyl Anniversary</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Today is our 33rd anniversary. In 4 months it will be 33-1/3. Then it will be a LP record.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 09:47:05 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/06/vinyl-anniversary/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/06/vinyl-anniversary/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Million Euro Overdraft</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;This happened over 9 years ago, I think it’s safe to tell the story now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my wife bought our first restaurant, she set up a corporation (GmbH) for the new business. However, our lawyer was lazy, or slow, or something, and for our start of business the registration of the GmbH had not yet been approved by the local court. No registration, no firm, no business loan could be paid out. With a 7-figure purchase price due that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No problem, says the bank, we’ll book the purchase from your private account, even though our account balance was more like 3 figures and not 7. We’ll increase your overdraft limit until the GmbH gets registered. No problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to this day I have a screenshot of electronic banking with an balance that day of minus one million Euros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought that was pretty funny until we tried to buy groceries and our bank card got denied. We had to call the bank again to increase our limit a bit more so we could eat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 18:56:33 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/08/05/million-euro-overdraft/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/08/05/million-euro-overdraft/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>1999.io is simple.  And simple.</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks I’ve been trying out &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/05/04/1238.html&quot;&gt;1999.io&lt;/a&gt;, the new blogging software by Dave Winer. You can either try it out at his site &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.1999.io&quot;&gt;my.1999.io&lt;/a&gt; (you just need a Twitter ID to log in) or you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scripting/1999-project/blob/master/docs/setup.md&quot;&gt;install the server&lt;/a&gt; on any system that can run Node. Being a server guy I of course installed my own (on a cheap 3.50€‚/mo VPS), and used it to write my last few blog posts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like it because because it’s simple. And simple. Simple to write with, simple to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple to write with. You just open the editor page and type. To update your text, you just click on it and type. There are some simple formatting options, but nothing that gets in the way. When you update, though WebSocket magic anyone reading your post immediately gets the update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on the server it’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://my.1999.io/users/1999io/2016/04/11/0004.html&quot;&gt;simple to work with&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no database, just files in open formats readable as text, JSON, OPML, RSS, HTML. Formats you can use for other purposes if you are so inclined. Even the HTML files for each post contain the JSON for the post, which I first thought was redundant but now see is brilliant. It’s like the web page contains it’s own DNA and can re-create itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These open formats allow one to do things with the output that go beyond the server. For instance, I copy the output of my server to an S3 bucket at &lt;a href=&quot;http://1999.papascott.de&quot;&gt;1999.papascott.de&lt;/a&gt;, which can probably handle load better than my cheap VPS :smile:. It’s not yet coupled to my main blog on Jekyll (right now I’m using copy and paste), but I imagine it wouldn’t too much cleverness to achieve that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope someday to be able to use 1999.io as a blogging central, with the ability to send my posts to my blog, or Twitter, or Facebook, or Medium, or wherever, but keeping my original posts for myself. I’ll let those big silos show my work, but not own it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 10:43:01 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/05/05/1999io-is-simple-and-simple/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/05/05/1999io-is-simple-and-simple/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Gliding 2</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nsF-UrqqkSQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how our son stays out of trouble on weekends. At 16 in Germany he can fly solo, but yet not drive a car. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 18:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/27/gliding-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/27/gliding-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to build 3000 pages in Jekyll in less than 4 seconds</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I converted my Wordpress blog to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. My 16 years of blogging are now saved as text files which Jekyll renders into static HTML, which I then push to GitHub where the blog is now hosted. I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/30/see-what-sticks/&quot;&gt;mentioned then&lt;/a&gt; that it took Jekyll some 3 minutes to render my 3000 or so blog posts, which is kind of a drag since the default is to rebuild the entire site every time even a small change is made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, the latest version of Jekyll improved build times considerably. It can now build my 3000 pages in about a minute. But when making changes, that’s still too long to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, using a trick, I can now build those 3000 pages in 4 seconds. The trick seems pretty obvious to me, but I’ve not seen it written up anyplace, so hence this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick, of course, is to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; build all 3000 pages. For older posts use &lt;a href=&quot;https://jquery.com/&quot;&gt;jquery&lt;/a&gt; to load in parts of the layout that might change, but leave the HTML file alone. For me, those parts are the sidebar and the recent posts. I build HTML snippets for those divs and load them in like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$( &quot;#sidebar&quot; ).load( &quot;/includes/sidebar.html&quot; );
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, on the Jekyll side I don’t want it to rebuild posts from before 2015. I’ve put all those in a _posts/older subdirectory and added an exclude: directive in my _config.yml:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;exclude: [_posts/older]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the HTML side, ever since I started blogging, even way-back-when with &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/davenet/1999/12/08/editthispagecom.html&quot;&gt;EditThisPage&lt;/a&gt;, my posts have been sorted by date. I need to tell Jekyll not to erase the pages I’ve chosen not to rebuild (and it’s too bad _config.yml doesn’t understand wild cards)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;keep_files: [archives/1999, archives/200, archives/2010, archives/2011, archives/2012, archives/2013, archives/2014 ]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least “archives/200” covers an entire decade in one entry. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it. When I do want to rebuild to entire site, I can comment out those two directives and let ‘er rip. And being hosted at GitHub, you can see all my gory source files in the source branch at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/papascott/papascott.github.io&quot;&gt;https://github.com/papascott/papascott.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 09:24:47 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/25/how-to-build-3000-pages-in-jekyll-in-less-than-4-seconds/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/04/25/how-to-build-3000-pages-in-jekyll-in-less-than-4-seconds/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>