<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>PapaScott</title>
		<description>And you know what they said? Well, some of it was true!</description>		
		<link>http://www.papascott.de</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.papascott.de/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>See What Sticks</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;So now that I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;/archives/2015/04/23/transition/&quot;&gt;changed&lt;/a&gt; my blogging platform, I have something to blog about: my new blogging platform!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the WordPress eXtended RSS file of the contents of my blog I found I had exported 3273 posts. Jekyll re-renders every post every time a change is made… on the default template it takes 3 minutes, but on the Lanyon template it ran over 20 minutes before I cancelled the build. That’s why I started with only a few dozen posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then changed my archive strategy, using yearly and monthly archives similar to what I had used with WordPress instead of the pagination used in Lanyon, and lo and behold the build took only 2.5 minutes. The disadvantage is that GitHub won’t run the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-archives&quot;&gt;jekyll-archives&lt;/a&gt; plugin for me, so I have to render the site locally and push the rendered HTML to GitHub. I can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next question was whether Google (and everyone else) could find the old links on the new site. Jekyll is able to use the same &lt;code&gt;archives/:year/:month/:day/:title/&lt;/code&gt; permalink stucture I was using before. But were all my links the same as before? Do they all still work? Well, that eXtended RSS file contains all the permalinks that WordPress had generated…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;http://papasc.home/archives/1999/12/05/it-worked/&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;http://papasc.home/archives/1999/12/06/week-37/&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;http://papasc.home/archives/1999/12/07/ready-and-waiting/&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;http://papasc.home/archives/1999/12/09/linux-fever/&amp;lt;/link&amp;gt;
 ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Yes, that’s a fake URL. My hoster timed out producing the eXtended RSS file so I had to use a local install.) I then ran the links through a shell script I found on &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/25135347/how-to-check-status-of-urls-from-text-file-using-bash-shell-script&quot;&gt;Stack Exchange&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; #!/bin/bash
 while read -ru 4 LINE; do
     read -r REP &amp;lt; &amp;lt;(exec curl -IsS &quot;$LINE&quot; 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1)
     echo &quot;$LINE: $REP&quot;
 done 4&amp;lt; &quot;$1&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, indeed, all the links work. Whether the content still makes sense is another question, but PapaScott is back online in its entirety!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/30/see-what-sticks/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/30/see-what-sticks/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Transition</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;So maybe you noticed, maybe you didn’t, but this blog looks a little bit different than a week ago. Behind the scenes it looks a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; different. After over a decade of blogging on WordPress (I actually started using its predecessor &lt;a href=&quot;http://cafelog.com/&quot;&gt;B2&lt;/a&gt; in 2002), I’m now on the static site generator jekyll. My posts have been exported to text files. No more mysql database, no PHP, no more web interface. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So everything is new and things are still broken. I don’t have all posts imported yet, I’m only back to 2012 and not 1999 when this thing started. There are a lot a worthless one-line posts from the olden days, since back then we didn’t have Twitter and Facebook yet for worthless posts. So I have some work to do. But I’m looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design, however, is absolutely fabulous, even on mobile, and for that I can take absolutely no credit. It’s the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lanyon.getpoole.com/&quot;&gt;lanyon&lt;/a&gt; theme for jekyll by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt;, who co-wrote (Twitter) &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, and I thank him for making his work available to us mere mortals. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/23/transition/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/23/transition/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Confirmation</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://policke1.p2-men.de/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/policke-200415.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Policke&quot; class=&quot;alignright&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Last week we bought a confirmation suit. Of course we went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://policke1.p2-men.de/&quot;&gt;Policke&lt;/a&gt; in Hamburg. It’s the perfect place for young (or older) men to shop. It has the feel of a 1920s haberdasher, full of dark little rooms connected by narrow halls and staircases. You’re met at the front door by the head sizer, who determines your size with a glance and with a slight movement of his eyes directs you to the room where your size is stocked. Once there, you nod at the salesman (they’re all men), who from your nod determines the style and price range you want. You’re in and out in 10 minutes. No words are necessary at any time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe not quite. :-) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confirmation will be at the end of May, on Pentecost Sunday. My mother will be flying in from the US. My father won’t be there, of course.  He made a huge impression on his grandson, though, despite living an ocean and thousands of miles away. He thought of his grandfather when he chose his confirmation verse*. We also legally added his grandfather’s name as an additional middle name for him. He will carry his grandfather’s name the rest of his life, and he will be confirmed with it next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess my father will be there after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Matthew 7:7 “Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/20/confirmation/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/04/20/confirmation/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How I Punked Facebook</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;It took me nearly two years, but I finally did it. I was able to get the better of Facebook. Yesterday I was able to celebrate my birthday without a single greeting on social media, even if my wife very nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/papascott/posts/10152947844446281y&quot;&gt;gave me away&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was heaven! It was bliss! I was living free of the distractions of the digital world, if only for one day. My day! For me, me alone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope your day was a good one too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 07:13:25 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/02/10/how-i-punked-facebook/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2015/02/10/how-i-punked-facebook/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Where Were You?</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Where was I 25 years ago as the Berlin Wall fell? I must confess, I don&#39;t remember exactly. If I had known the news would radically change our lives, I might have paid more attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn&#39;t realize it at the time, but our lives in November 1989 were &quot;in between&quot;. In between jobs, in between continents, in between everything. We had just moved to Arizona, following her old boss who didn&#39;t have a job for her yet. I was working temp jobs hoping to find something permanent (one of them eventually did). We thought Arizona would become our home. We were in love with the desert, the sun, the lifestyle, everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had, however, picked a horrible time to move to Arizona. The savings and loan crisis had broken out, and the economy was already stagnant. And in the weeks and months that followed, the soon-to-be-reunified Germany became more attractive to us. We thought we could work there for a couple years and come back when the job climate in Arizona was better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where was I when I heard the news? Today I have no idea. In my car listening to NPR? At home watching CNN? With my wife when she got a call from her Hungarian friend Gabi? I just know that less than 10 months later, we were here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 17:59:03 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/11/09/where-were-you/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/11/09/where-were-you/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Thank you to everyone for everything</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who sent condolences for my father, be it on PapaScott, Facebook, Twitter or even with written words on paper. I debated posting publically about my feelings, and now I&#39;m glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m currently &quot;between the continents&quot;, so to speak. I returned yesterday from the US, and fly today to Dubrovnik for 4 days on business. I still have some thoughts on the past week, the funeral, the Midwestern traditions, and the hotdish. I&#39;ll share them once I get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 06:08:07 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/10/11/thank-you-to-everyone-for-everything/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/10/11/thank-you-to-everyone-for-everything/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Absence</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;My father died Thursday morning, age 81. I wasn&#39;t there yet, I had only made it as far as London. He was always impatient, he never liked waiting for anyone when he was ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not like we weren&#39;t ready for this. He&#39;s been on oxygen for 11 years, at first only at night, and later 24 hours. I always wondered how I would feel when the time came. Now I know. I feel his absence. Absence, as in the opposite of presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&#39;m home with my mother and brother to together go through the rituals. We spoke with the funeral home yesterday, made the decisions, gave details for the obituary, looked at the plot, picked out flowers. Viewing is Sunday afternoon, prayer service that evening, funeral 10:30 Monday morning. We tried to do things to make it informal and not all too a somber and sad affair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zahrbockfuneralhome.com/obituaries.php&quot;&gt;obituary will be online&lt;/a&gt;. That&#39;s a thing now I guess. If you have Flash music will play, you may want to turn it down first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our son arrives from Germany today. He brought his bagpipes. I hope he&#39;s up to playing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 13:08:14 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/10/04/absence/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/10/04/absence/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Godmorgen</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to spend some money on ourselves rather than the business for a change. When we built our house back in 1996, when we got to designing the bathroom we had run out of both money and imagination. We ended with boring hospital-white. We* tore everything out, replaced and rearranged the fixtures, threw out the tub, built a new wall, replaced the door and window, and installed a walk-in spa-like shower. After two and half weeks without a bath, it&#39;s done enough that we can use it. We&#39;re missing a few details yet, like towel hooks, toilet paper dispenser, mirrors, and cabinets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Of course, &quot;we did&quot; actually means &quot;we hired professionals to do&quot;, but we did build the Ikea Godmorgen sink cabinet ourselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I&#39;ve now added panorama photos und put them all in a Flickr album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&#39;position: relative; padding-bottom: 76%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#39;&gt;&lt;iframe id=&#39;iframe&#39; src=&#39;http://flickrit.com/slideshowholder.php?height=75&amp;size=big&amp;setId=72157644926436595&amp;thumbnails=0&amp;transition=0&amp;layoutType=responsive&amp;sort=0&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39;style=&#39;width:100%; height:100%; position: absolute; top:0; left:0;&#39; &gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 11:35:17 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/05/30/godmorgen/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/05/30/godmorgen/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Phone Tricks 2014</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;To keep in touch with home I find it handy to have an US phone number. We never got in the habit of using Skype; a cordless phone is just a lot handier than turning on the PC. For a while I had a US Skype Number with a Minnesota area code. However, at €5 a month it&#39;s not that cheap, and worse, my parents were not able to reach the number from their cell phones. And if I forward the calls to our regular German number, I pay Skype rates for the privilege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did some hunting around, and discovered the VOIP provider &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anveo.com/consumer/default.asp&quot;&gt;Anveo&lt;/a&gt; offers US numbers pay-as-you-go for $2 a month (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anveo.com/consumer/mainphonenumbers.asp&quot;&gt;&quot;Personal Unlimited&quot;&lt;/a&gt; plan). You can then forward the calls to a regular number at their normal rates, but since we have VOIP at home anyway, I just set them up as an additional account and pay nothing. Calls to the US cost $0.01 per minute, slightly cheaper than our main provider. They have servers in both the US and Germany. We&#39;ve been with them for 2 months, and they seem to work just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you&#39;re wondering, our main VOIP (for home and home office) is on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sipgate.de/team/voip&quot;&gt;Sipgate Team&lt;/a&gt; with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.de/gp/product/B004U6NTXU/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1638&amp;amp;creative=19454&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B004U6NTXU&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=papascott-21&quot;&gt;Gigaset C610 IP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//ir-de.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=papascott-21&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=3&amp;amp;a=B004U6NTXU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt; base station. I tried first with a Fritz Box, but never managed to get it working reliably, probably because the Fritz Box was not our router, but behind our router.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other trick to plan mobile phone and data for our visits to the US. Prepaid credit expires quickly in the States, so if you&#39;re there just once or twice a year it&#39;s likely cheapest to set up something new each year. This year we&#39;re trying service from &lt;a href=&quot;http://goredpocket.com/&quot;&gt;Red Pocket&lt;/a&gt; sold by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reisesim.de/&quot;&gt;ReiseSIM.de&lt;/a&gt; in Germany. The SIMs are pre-activated, you can add credit before your trip, and you can dial direct without going through a gateway to call Germany. Calls are $0.10/min in the US and $0.11/min to Germany. Network is ATT, and for the data plans &lt;a href=&quot;http://goredpocket.com/plans#gsmt-mi&quot;&gt;&quot;tethering is encouraged&quot;&lt;/a&gt; (that was our mistake last year, no tethering, and we constantly fought over the one tablet with internet). Our son will be taking a phone on his Easter trip to Minnesota, and we&#39;re in Orlando for business at the end of April, so we&#39;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 09:20:30 +0200</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/03/31/phone-tricks-2014/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/03/31/phone-tricks-2014/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>B-52&#39;s</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;253&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9SOryJvTAGs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EXCLUSIVE CONTENT: I&#39;ve hidden my birthday on Facebook, but you might be able to guess my new age from the title of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 09:39:32 +0100</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/02/09/b-52s/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2014/02/09/b-52s/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>