<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>PapaScott</title>
		<description>I don't claim to succeed at all this!</description>		
		<link>http://www.papascott.de</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.papascott.de/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Travis CI</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, I figured out how to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://travis-ci.org/&quot; title=&quot;Travis CI - Test and Deploy Your Code with Confidence&quot;&gt;Travis CI&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://pauldambra.github.io/using-travis-to-build-jekyll.html&quot; title=&quot;Using Travis CI to build a Jekyll site&quot;&gt;build my Jekyll blog&lt;/a&gt; and push it to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot; title=&quot;Websites for you and your projects&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, and figured that I would actually write something for it to build rather than just fiddle with scripts and yaml files in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 12:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2017/07/23/travis-ci/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2017/07/23/travis-ci/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Future Part 2</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;ul class=&quot;photo-gallery&quot;&gt;
  
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/gallery/rdz-win3.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;1&quot; title=&quot;Kiosks&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gallery/rdz-win3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kiosks&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/gallery/rdz-win1.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;1&quot; title=&quot;Front Counter and McCafé&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gallery/rdz-win1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front Counter and McCafé&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/gallery/rdz-win2.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;1&quot; title=&quot;McCafé Lounge with 'Broken' Logo&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gallery/rdz-win2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;McCafé Lounge with 'Broken' Logo&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/gallery/rdz-win4.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;1&quot; title=&quot;Front Counter&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gallery/rdz-win4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front Counter&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last fall we converted our restaurant in Dibbersen into a &lt;a href=&quot;/archives/2016/11/07/the-future-is-now/&quot;&gt;Restaurant of the Future&lt;/a&gt;. Now we’ve remodeled our Hamburg, Winsener Straße restaurant so now we have doubled the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lobby here has a more urban theme that fits our gritty part of Hamburg. I was worried it would be too dark, but the spots of color make it look brighter live than it appears in the photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It of course has all the innovations in Dibbersen, plus we now serve “Barista Quality” coffee at the front counter, meaning that the espresso drinks are made with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wmf-espresso.de/index_en.php#coffee-machine-section&quot;&gt;portafilter machine&lt;/a&gt; in McCafé.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this future we need to take time to catch our breaths. Our 3rd drive-thru restaurant on the Autobahn A1 at Rade will join the future in early 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 09:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2017/02/26/the-future-part-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2017/02/26/the-future-part-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Song of the Day: I Can't Drive 55</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RvV3nn_de2k&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
This isn’t for me, despite the title, but I’ll take it. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KUEW9Fr0Xbs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 05:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2017/02/09/song-of-the-day-i-cant-drive-55/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2017/02/09/song-of-the-day-i-cant-drive-55/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Future Is Now</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;We were closed 11 days for construction, but now our restaurant in Dibbersen has been opened for 3 days as a “Restaurant of the Future” and so far we are very happy with it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/rdz-kiosks-061116.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;alignright&quot; /&gt; The first thing you notice as a guest is the brighter, more spacious lobby, as well as the self-service terminals, or kiosks. There you can enter your order and pay by either card or cash. Of course you can still go to the cashier and verbally give your order just as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing you notice is that the cashier does not then go to assemble your order. There is a separate station for that, and you can either go there to pick up your order, or you can choose table service. You pick up a chip, find a table, and thanks to the magic of bluetooth we can find your table and bring your order to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third thing you notice is that all burgers are made fresh to order. This “Made For You” system has been running for years in the US, but is new in Germany. The heated bin&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; where products could be kept for 10 minutes is now history. Our products are now made one at time instead of an entire tray at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were wondering how quickly we could adjust to the new system, but the first 3 days went very well. The kitchen is more organized and less hectic, and even it gets full we can recover quite quickly. In service our people enjoy that they now have time and opportunity to talk to our guests, and with our new look and new system they have plenty to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even I learned enough about the new system that I can help out in the kitchen without messing everything up. :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Funny how in US English a bin is where you put things to keep, but in UK English a bin is where you put things to throw away.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 06:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/07/the-future-is-now/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/07/the-future-is-now/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>If Clinton Wins</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of days ago Dave Winer wrote a piece about &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/10/30/imOkayWithTrumpWinning.html&quot;&gt;Trump winning&lt;/a&gt;. So what if Clinton wins?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be like the status quo only worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large group of Trump who feel estranged from the system will still feel estranged. This estrangement is certainly not exclusively American, see Brexit, the &lt;em&gt;Front National&lt;/em&gt;, or the &lt;em&gt;Alternativ für Deutschland&lt;/em&gt;. This group will remain and I doubt that Clinton is the type of leader that can win them back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republican party will remain dysfunctional, maybe even to the point that no Supreme Court justices will be confirmed at all. Look forward to more standstill and government shutdowns. The “Lock Her Up” faction will not become silent, they’ll probably become louder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abroad, relations with Russia will continue to worsen and the conflicts of the world will continue, with new ones arising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, though, we’ll be pretty happy with it, because &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2016/10/30/imOkayWithTrumpWinning.html&quot;&gt;it could have been much worse!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 10:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/02/if-clinton-wins/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/02/if-clinton-wins/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Expecting</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;On this All Saints’ Day we are happy and proud to announce that we are expecting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, no, that’s not right… damn you auto-correct, we’re too old for that. No, we are happy and proud to announce that we are &lt;em&gt;expanding&lt;/em&gt;, in Hamburg-Harburg!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/phxarc-011116.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On December 1st we will be purchasing the existing McDonald’s restaurants in Phoenix Center and Harburg Arcaden. They are so-called satellites, located in shopping centers with a limited menu and low volume (about 1/3 the sales of a free-standing restaurant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already own the Marktkauf Center satellite in Harburg, and all three stores are just a couple hundred meters apart. Our store manager there will now have her hands full with triplets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as we are right now converting our restaurant in Dibbersen to Restaurant of the Future (re-opening on Friday!) with Winsener Straße to follow in February, Frauke and I have our hands full too! :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 09:56:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/01/expecting/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/11/01/expecting/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Done!</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;It took 10 years to build and is 10 times over budget, but the Hamburg’s new concert hall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elbphilharmonie.de/en/elbphilharmonie&quot;&gt;Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; in the HafenCity is complete. The first concert is in January, but the builders handed it over to the city today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Live from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Hamburg?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Hamburg&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Elbphilharmonie?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; is ready for opening (window lighting reads &amp;#39;DONE&amp;#39; in German: FERTIG) &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/l5pLLaBSkS&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/l5pLLaBSkS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Thomas Michael G. (@ThomasMichaelGe) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ThomasMichaelGe/status/793127825909878785&quot;&gt;October 31, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the day it looks more like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;de&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Hoffentlich schwindelfrei ;) Fensterputzer an der &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Elbphilharmonie?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Elbphilharmonie&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/RX3IYSu8XU&quot;&gt;https://t.co/RX3IYSu8XU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bild: Marek Santen &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/v5Mc6sLJal&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/v5Mc6sLJal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; hamburg.de (@hamburg_de) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hamburg_de/status/793082218545635328&quot;&gt;October 31, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 17:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/10/31/done/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/10/31/done/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Stupid Majority</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;This election is a good reminder of the basic principles of democracy: stupid people vote. Not only that, any democracy is ruled by a stupid majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it. If you believe that you are of above-average intelligence, and who of us doesn’t, then by definition there is a majority of voters more stupid than you. And since stupid people generally don’t recognize their own stupidity, almost every one of us is faced with a stupid majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are stupid, and you know it, you can rest assured that there is a smart majority out there to make the decisions for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the average person, of average intelligence, the average person has a great responsibility. They have the deciding vote. They decide whether the majority is smart or stupid. Our fate rests in their hands. May they choose wisely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they can’t. They are only of average intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we are doomed to be ruled by a stupid majority. But that is not altogether a bad thing. All the political systems where only smart people make decisions have failed very badly. It is the stupid people who save us from ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And I bet you thought a post with this title would be about Trump supporters. Or Clinton supporters. Fooled you!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 19:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/23/the-stupid-majority/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/23/the-stupid-majority/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Fifteen Years On</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/nyTimesHomeBombing7AM2.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/nyt-110916.gif&quot; alt=&quot;New York Times Screenshot 9-11-2001 via scripting.com &quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This screenshot from &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/images/nyTimesHomeBombing7AM2.gif&quot;&gt;scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; is pretty much how I first learned the the 9/11 attacks. A low-res picture on a news website from my office in Hamburg. 3 in the afternoon. The next day I was able to put my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/12/the-day-the-earth-stood-still/&quot;&gt;thoughts into words&lt;/a&gt;. More or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And next day came the headline in the Hamburg newspaper &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/13/were-in-this-together/&quot;&gt;“Americans! We are with you!”&lt;/a&gt;, and at the same time, the first clue that the attackers came from Hamburg. All I knew then was that my country and world would never be the same again. I was far away, and grateful for the internet where I could at least try to fathom how the country I had left a few years before was changing. Without me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And today. My son who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papascott.de/archives/2001/09/16/sunday-at-home/&quot;&gt;was an 1 year old then&lt;/a&gt; is now 16, nearly an adult. My country started two wars in revenge that solved nothing, made everything worse, and haven’t really yet ended. Mission not accomplished. The current round of politics and presidential candidates don’t seem to offer much hope of any improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think I’ll just listen to &lt;a href=&quot;http://brucespringsteen.net/albums/the-rising&quot;&gt;The Rising&lt;/a&gt; a couple times through to remind of me of how I felt and how things could have become better. But didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 19:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/11/fifteen-years-on/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/11/fifteen-years-on/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Vinyl Anniversary</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;Today is our 33rd anniversary. In 4 months it will be 33-1/3. Then it will be a LP record.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 07:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/06/vinyl-anniversary/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.papascott.de/archives/2016/09/06/vinyl-anniversary/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>